TYLER WILLIAMS

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I'm Tyler Williams, a full stack developer with 4 years of professional experience focusing on building highly responsive and adaptive web In my freetime, I build proofs of concept for my team utilizing React, Webpack, Graphql in order to solution for a more efficent, minified and performant projects at scale. I always keep the readability and maintainability of my code a top priority, while constantly running performance optimizations which allows me to adapt to various work flows and demands from product owners and management.

CONTACT

3218 N. Clark Street, APT. 510, CHICAGO, IL. 60657

- **1** 607 882 0531
- 🗐 tyler.scott.14@gmail.com
- math https://tylerscottwilliams.com

SKILLS

JAVASCRIPT PHP **JQUERY** LESS/SASS HTML5 MYSQL WORDPRESS NODEJS REACT ADOBE PHOTOSHOP CC POSTGRESQL GRUNT GULP WEBPACK VISUAL STUDIO ANGULARJS CSS3 **PYTHON** JAVA MONGODR ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR CC AWS NEO4J DIGITALOCEAN GIT BASH **TERMINAL** GRAPHQL REST/API REDUX / MOBX BABEL / ES6 JIRA / CONFLUENCE

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

March 2018 - Present

Footlocker - Chicago, IL

Actively working alongside a multidisciplinary team of engineers to design and developa multi-site/multi-brand, React single page, server side rendered ecommerce application. Utilizing modern frameworks and technologies, I have helped architect and implement a new rewards program as well as a new single sign on platform for the online Footlocker Branded experience.

Interactive Frontend Web Developer

March 2017 - March 2018

Macy's - New York, New York
While working alongside 10 of

While working alongside 10 other developers, I build and maintain all online branding websites for Macy's.com. Projects are constructed utilizing Node.js, Handlebars, SASS, jQuery, and React to deliver the most responsive and interactive e-commerce sites for all modern browsers and every major platform. Before development begins, I collaborate with several other departments, to coordinate ideas and retrieve analytic requirements to produce a well engineered final product, which is then sent to our QA team. Because of Macy's growing online footprint, I also provide swift debugging support for other teammates to ensure site reliability while also juggling side projects and proofs of concepts to potentially improve project work flow.

Frontend Web Developer

September 2015 - March 2017

Dressler-LLC - New York, New York

Conceived, implemented, and managed large-scale optimizely A/B and Multi-variant user experiments in order to construct unique and highly performant front-end experiences. Alongside a team of several other developers, I built and maintained extensive Wordpress multi-sites and custom plugins for Wiley Efficient Learning, Springbank, LeeCo. I have also worked with 9/11 Museum and Memorial, Oliver Scholars, Pennsaid and Gusto, utilizing PHP, Javascript, Jquery and CSS3 among other languages and libraries.

Teaching Assistant

August 2014 - May 2015

Cornell University Dept. of Information Science

Organized, planned, and instructed weekly programming labs to aid in upcoming course content to a section of 15+ students. Held weekly office hours to aid students in troubleshooting and debugging their code. Managed the online student forums providing answers to technical programming questions and language specific peculiarities relevant to the course material.

Frontend Web Developer Intern

May 2014 - August 2014

Dressler-LLC - New York, New York

Developed 4+ production-ready responsive websites and widgets for several fortune 500 companies. Promoted such long-term success that a new permanent position was created to continue the work from this internship. Incorporated various web technologies into new work-flow which facilitated rapid prototyping and deployment of websites for clients.

EDUCATION

Cornell University, BA

Information Science | 2010 - 2015

My primary course load was built around the architecture of large scale information systems, desktop and mobile game design, information retrieval, database design and structures, networks, and building data driven web applications.

Cornell University, BFA

Fine Arts - Photography | 2010 - 2015

With computer science in mind, my work was largely concentrated around digital artwork with a senior thesis centered on utilizing Twitter's API to read and then analyse tweets to generate music from the analysis.